Register of the Jeannette Bell Papers, 1983-1996
Wisconsin Historical Society
Jeannette Bell Papers, 1983-1996
Bell, Jeannette
M91-072; M93-207; M97-042
6.6 c.f.
Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division
Papers of Jeannette Bell, a Democratic representative of Wisconsins 15th Assembly District (the West Allis area), 1982-1996. Included are files documenting her legislative interests, particularly her work on child abuse issues, sexual predator and stalking laws, and files accumulated during her term as member and chair of the Environmental Resources Committee. The collection contains committee, legislative, and issue files which include background information, notes from meetings, press releases, correspondence, reports, prepared testimony, and drafts of bills; and Bells newsletters, speeches, and press releases.
This collection was received in multiple parts from the donor(s) and is organized into 3 major parts. These materials have not been physically interfiled and researchers might need to consult more than one part to locate similar materials.
Part 1 (M91-072): Original Collection, 1983-1996
Part 2 (M93-207): Additions, 1982-1992
Part 3 (M97-042): Additions, 1983-1996
Administrative/Restriction Information
Presented by Jeannette Bell, West Allis, Wisconsin. M91-072, M93-207, M97-042
Contents List
- Part 1 (M91-072): Original Collection, 1983-1996, M91-072; 2.6 c.f. (2 record center cartons and 2 archives boxes)
  Papers of Bell, a Democratic representative of Wisconsin's 15th Assembly District (the West Allis area), 1982-1990, including interspersed correspondence, brochures and pamphlets; reports and government bills/hearings and press releases related to committees, boards and legislature on environmental issues in Wisconsin. Materials primarily focus on issues related to air, water and waste pollution.
  - Acid rain, federal (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Radioactive waste, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Superfund information, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Repair Fund, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Governor's Clean Water Task Force, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Well contamination, correspondence and information, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Sewage systems funding, Milwaukee Metropolitan Sewerage District, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA), hazardous and solid waste amendments, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - NR 105, NR 106, Natural Resources Board, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Environmental issues, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Low level radioactive waste, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Water diversion, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Environment, groundwater, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Parks and recreation, Ice Age Trail, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Regulatory review, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Nonpoint soil erosion and water control, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nonpoint pollution storm water management, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Low Level Radioactive Waste Commission, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ozone, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Acid Rain, 1985-1990
    - Fifth Annual Report on Great Lakes Water Quality (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Reports and correspondence (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Consolidated Papers, Incorporated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Proposed legislation (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Intergovernmental Conference on Acid Rain, proceedings (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Dairyland Power Cooperative, Interim Report (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and reports (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Well Contamination, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Environmental Resources Committee records, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Part 2 (M93-207): Additions, 1982-1992, M93-207; 0.6 c.f. (2 archives boxes)
  Additions: files include press releases by year, 1982-1992, and news columns by year, 1983-1992.
- Part 3 (M97-042): Additions, 1983-1996, M97-042; 3.4 c.f. 3.4 c.f. (3 record center cartons and 1 archives box)
  Additions, 1983-1996, including committee, board and legislative issue files, speeches and newsletters reference files on sexual predator and stalking laws and on corporal punishment, and press releases, 1991-1992.
  - Child Abuse and Neglect Prevention Board
    - Reporting requirements, AB 529, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - General, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Family Resource Center, child abuse, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Speeches
    - 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Quotable quotes, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Background material, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Committee, legislation, and issue files
    - Children's Trust Fund, 1984-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
    - Development zones, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - AIDS legislation for sanitation workers, AB 743, LRB 1952, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Joint Legislative Council Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - National Conference of State Legislature (NCSL) Task Force, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Committee on the University and Economic Development, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Women's Cancer Coalition of Suburban Milwaukee, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Boy Scouts West District Nominating Committee, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Children's Group, Raising Children Without Violence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Child Abuse and Neglect Reporting Requirements (CANRR), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Displaced Homemaker Advisory Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Task Force on Federalism, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Headlight Bill - AB 618, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Barber licensing (Rental of Chair from another Barber), 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Cargo Trucks Excluded from Left Lane on Expressway, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Examining Board Requirements, therapist misconduct, AB 567, LRB 0958, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Increase penalty for sexual misconduct by therapists, AB 568, LRB 0282, 1996-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Prohibit party affiliation questions, AB 577, LRB 3894, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ways and Means, AB 775 and 776, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Inclusion of Telephone Numbers on Political Communications, AB 340, LRB 2475, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Merge city police or fire departments, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Tax recreational property at higher rates, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Industrial mobile air conditioners fee charge, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Buck and Bear Club resolution, AJR 19, LRB 0131, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Raising insurance eligibility to 70, AB 84, LRB 0035, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Social Security numbers on drivers license, AB 85, LRB 0551, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Scanning Bill draft, AB 428, LRB 0058, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Consumer Audit Act, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Telecommunications bill, Act 496, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Custody case, two year period, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Newsletters, 1983-1996 (Box 2, Folder 21-35)
    - Graphics, undated, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sexual predator and stalking laws reference files
    - Sexual predators, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Stalking, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Miniskirt Bill, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Notre Dame Law Review, anti-stalking laws, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Old stalking, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Anti-stalking bills, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Stalking materials, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Stalking, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Illinois law, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Legislative Council Special Committee on Children in Need of Protection or Services, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Legislative Council Special Committee on Children in Need of Protection or Services, 1993-1995 (continued) (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Corporal punishment reference files
    - General, 1984-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bill supporters, AB 799, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Corporal punishment in schools, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Caning, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Spanking bill, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Mailing, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Children, 1985-1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Press releases
    - 1991
      - Press conference, February 11 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Government revenue increases, budget, March 15 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - April 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Bugher letter and Bell's response, April 3 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - April 17 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Notes from WHA radio, Bell's Interview, April 17 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Press conference, Assembly Parlor, May 8 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Letter to Welch, May 28 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - WMC radio campaign response, May 29 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - W.A. papers, Bell, Leean plan, June 3 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Alchemist Governor, June 5 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Governor Blitz against Leean/Bell proposal, June 11 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Lawsuit request, July 24 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - News column, Executive Forum, Milwaukee Journal, July 24 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - August 6, not released (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Public forum, small business funds, August 13 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Education vetoes, August 28 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Linton, Andrea, Schwartz, September 25 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Summit meeting proposed by bell, September 9 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Tax relief summit, September 13 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Lottery Funds a Shell Game, October 2 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - TIF aid, October 2 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Press conference - Wineke, Hisrich, Rohan, and Grobschmidt, October 18 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - School spending increases, November 21 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Cost per member increases, December 5 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Cost controls, spending increases, December 30 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1992
      - Education reform package, no tax relief, January 17 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Fair Tax Amendment, January 22 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Opinion to W.A. Star Enterprise, Governor's budget adjustment bill, February 13 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Fair Tax Amendment, February 17 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
      - Governor's budget bill, deduction changes, February 21 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Cost control final proposal, meeting notice, March 13 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Bell responds to Governor's criticism of cost controls, March 20 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Fair Tax Amendment, October 14 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Summit meeting, November (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Small business initiative, November 12 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Pre-1993 May (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Caucus news columns, ideas (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Copies (Box 4, Folder 15)